Mohammad Totonchy

Mohammad.totonchyy@outlook.com | mohtotonchy.com 0426 038 779

Professional Summary

A highly motivated frontend engineer with a determined passion for building web applications with great user experiences.

Technical Skills

Technologies: Firebase v9, Git, GitHub, React Developer Tools, framer Motion

Proficient: HTML5, CSS3 (SCSS + BEM), JavaScript ES6+, Typescript, ReactJS, NodeJS ,expressJS

Familiar: NextJS, MaterialUI, tailwind, Redux, mongoDB, SQL

Experience

Associate software Engineer

Jan 2023 - current

Versent

- Developed and maintained 3 Restful APIs using c# for HBF.
- React was used to test certain codes on the frontend.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams including designers, product managers, and other developers to create high-quality products.
- Part of a team migrating MuleSoft to AWS for Curtin University using Typescript and cdk
- Error handling app code created and structured to allow for flexibility to handle different types of errors throughout the project.
- Unit testing using JEST was implemented to mock real functions and apis endpoints to ensure functionality is met.
- Actively participated in daily stand-up meetings, providing updates on progress and any potential impediments to team members.
- Integrated **Slack and Confluence** to enhance team communication, collaboration, and knowledge sharing within the agile development environment.
- Facilitated effective communication and encouraged open discussions during sprint retrospectives to identify areas for improvement and implement actionable changes.

Freelance Frontend Developer

Apr 2022 – **Jan** 2023

Self Employed

- Delivered 5 professional websites using HTML5, CSS3 (+ SCSS, BEM), JavaScript and React best practises.
- · Improved website performance by compressing, caching and lazy loading images and components
- Included SEO, responsive, multi-platform and hosting support, enabling their website to be used by any browser or device in the world.

Frontend Developer Support

May 2022 – Jul 2022

Frontend Simplified

- Supported 1,000+ students using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript and React best practises
- Utilized debugging best practises using Google Chrome inspect element tooling
- Simplified difficult programming concepts including responsive website development, CSS layout, Promises and API requests

Projects

Gmail Clone | GitHub

- Created a fully responsive Gmail application.
- HTML, CSS, JS AND REACT, REDUX
- functionality (Google Sign-In, Firebase)

Twitter Clone | GitHub

- Developed a social media app.
- HTML, CSS, JS, REACT AND REDUX

Google Clone | GitHub

Integrated Google's API to create a real-world search engine with HTML, CSS, JS, REACT AND REDUX

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science (Software Engineering Major)

Nov 2024

Frontend Developer Bootcamp

Apr 2022 - Sep 2022

Frontend Simplified

Referees

Available upon request.